Information Architect / UX Researcher

Address: 603 Chemin de Charveyron 01420 Corbonod - France

> Mobile: +33 6 33.04.44.17 consorti.simonetta@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE and KEY SKILLS

Dedicated and professional User Experience Manager with a focus on Information Architecture and Usability. Broad experience in the international environment. Expert in user interface design, usability testing and user research in the European and international markets both in the private and humanitarian sectors. Proficiency in defining efficient navigation and information architectures for CMS driven websites and web-based applications. Broad experience in estimating, planning, managing web-teams, facilitating workshops and usability testing.

• Client Relations

• User-centered Design

• Interpersonal Communication

• Process Definition

Multi-disciplinary Teamwork

• Research and Analysis

• Problem Solving

• Team Building and Leading

• Detail Orientation

CAREER HISTORY

Information Architect

World Health Org (WHO/WMO) – Geneva May 2018 – July 2019

- Design approach and plan, UX Research, Concept and High Level Design: agree and document a participatory user-centered approach and plan for the design phase of the Health and Climate Science Portal. Conduct interviews with key user groups to define Mental Model and personas. Research user profile analytics and benchmark of key functionalities. Define website concept, high level sitemap and key pages design, content management and back-office strategy.
- <u>Usability Review & Usability Testing</u> of newly developed Pre-Qualification System: review technical documentation and dynamic prototype against usability standards; define a low fidelity prototype for a section of the tool and share it with the clients remotely, prepare usability testing.

Climate & Clean Air Coalition (CCAC) - Paris Information Architect Jun 2016 - May 2018

- Information Architecture & Testing for CCAC main website: define information architecture (content type definition, detailed sitemap, wireframes of website screens and CMS screens), conduct card sorting to test resource types, provide support to implementation [http://www.ccacoalition.org]
- User Research, Information Architecture & Usability Testing for internal reporting tool (phase 1 & 2): visualize business processes (process diagrams), define information architecture (screen flows and wireframes), conduct usability testing, provide support to implementation

Information Architect

ILO - Geneva

Jul 2011 - Dec 2017

Maternity leave: Aug 2011 - Aug 2012; Jul 2014 - Dec 2014 & Jan - May 2016

- Information Architecture for an internal tool: define process flows and information architecture (detailed sitemap, wireframes, data structure) for an internal application used by the ILO Medical Services department to manage appointments, patient records and stocks.
- Customer Journey Maps and Personas: develop customer journey maps and personas to describe the use of ILO social media, print and web channels
- Usability Testing for ILO Global website (desktop and mobile): test plan definition and implementation, usability testing report, information architecture recommendations based on testing result [www.ilo.org]
- Evaluation and Information Architecture for ILO Helpdesk for Business: usability review, user interviews and Mental Model definition, information architecture based on evaluation recommendations.
- Mental Model Research: define audience segments, set up and conduct interviews, comb interviews for tasks, facilitate workshops, build Mental Model Diagram to show ILO users' tasks and supporting products/services.
- Information Architecture for ILO Legislation Analysis Database (in collaboration with Studio Gnot): gather requirements, design and present information architecture documentation for a new ILO database facilitating quantitative and qualitative legislation analysis.
- <u>Usability Testing</u> and <u>Information Architecture</u> for ILO FAST search engine: test plan definition, usability testing implementation, information architecture recommendations based on testing result [www.ilo.org].

Information Architect

UNISDR and UNAIDS - Geneva

Jan 2014 - Jul 2014

- UNISDR: Technical Documentation and High Level Architecture: definition of documentation standards and reverse engineering of UNISDR Contact Management System (wireframes and screen flow diagrams); definition of PreventionWeb.net high level architecture (sketches).
- UNAIDS: <u>Usability Testing</u> for AIDSInfo data visualization tool HIV data visualized through maps, graphs, tables (http://aidsinfo.unaids.org). Test plan definition, usability testing implementation, testing report.

Information Architect/Project Manager (P3 level)

User Research and Information Architecture for the design of CMS driven websites and web applications in Disaster Risk Reduction:

- User Research: user interviews, mental model and alignment diagram definition, ethnographic research
- Information Architecture: design of high level sitemap, detailed sitemap, wireframes, screen flows and navigation models for websites and content management systems; faceted search interface design and testing, search results tuning, search logs and search monitoring interface design, design patterns library.
- Usability Testing: test plan definition, recipients' recruitment and usability testing implementation
- Project Management: support in the definition of the project plan and internal processes; coordination with external counterparts (Visual Design, Web Development and Usability Testing); support in the preparation of full-day meetings and workshops

PROJECTS

PreventionWeb portal [www.preventionweb.net], Global Platform for Disaster Risk Reduction websites and internal systems, **UNISDR** website [www.unisdr.org] and intranet, **IRP** recovery portal [www.recoveryplatform.org], **DRH** website [drh.edm.bosai.go.jp], **IASC Early Warning Early Action** internal reporting system, FAST Search Engine customization for disaster reduction websites, Global Risk Data **Platform** [http://preview.grid.unep.ch].

Information Architect/Lead Sapient – London and Milan

Apr 2001 - Jun 2006

User Experience Lead (multi-disciplinary teams: internal and client)

- Defining approach and processes for large projects and programs; detailing scope documents, estimating, planning, pricing, team sizing, allocating resources for large scale/multi-track projects
- Managing multi-track and multi-disciplinary teams, both internal teams and client teams
- Monitoring status, creating status reports and analysis, defining creative solutions for issue management and risk management, preparing project documentation for external project reviews
- Team building and motivating; people growth; coaching creative teams; facilitating lessons learnt sessions
- Reviewing creative design deliverables and technical deliverables for Quality Assurance
- Engaging clients; developing and retaining client relationships; engaging third parties and suppliers
- Planning, preparing, organising and facilitating internal and client workshops; presenting team work and deliverables to clients working groups and steering committees; preparing and presenting sales material

Information Architect/Content Strategist

- Information architecture and navigation definition for web sites and web-based solutions (including CMS and LMS); design of sitemaps, wireframes, screen flows and navigation models.
- Support of client-side and competitor benchmarking in specific market segments; design, execution and analysis of usability testing on web sites and prototypes; static and dynamic prototype design.
- UE support to implementation; standards definition for hand-off documentation to the technology teams.
- Requirements analysis, concept modeling, approach definition for User Experience Design teams.
- Documentation/Material assessing, analyzing and archiving for web sites and web-based solutions.
- Content type design and content definition; content migration support and content life-cycle definition

PROJECTS

UK Department of Health website and CMS, Vodafone UK intranet and global intranet, BP websites migration to a global internet platform, Hotels.com (Expedia) websites, db mortgages intermediaries' website, Bticino website and extranet, Merloni LMS, Intesa Formazione website, Wind website, Ferrari owner's website, Maserati website.

Information Architect

Giunti / ACTA / Politecnico - Milan

Apr 1999 - Jul 2002

Laboratories in Information Architecture and Web Design, book publishing, design and testing of CD ROMs

LANGUAGE SKILLS & TRAINING

- Language skills: Italian: English: French: German (basic): Spanish (basic)
- Training: Project Management, People Management, Advanced Information Architecture, Web Writing, Usability Testing Techniques, Search Engine Usability, Web Forms Usability, Mental Modelling

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

- Master's Degree in Communication Sciences, Oct 1993 Mar 1999, University of Bologna
- Certificate Program in Web Publishing and Information Architecture, Apr-Jun 2000, UC San Diego